Guide to the Amos Vogel Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Films, 1896-2001
  - Subseries II.5: Subject Files, 1947-2001
    - Poop Sheets
      - One from the Heart, 1982 (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper Tiger Television, 1983 (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - 1983-1984
        - General, 1983-1984 (Box 98, Folder 6)
        - General, 1983-1984 (Box 99, Folder 1)
        - The Good Fight, 1984 (Box 99, Folder 2)
        - Heimat, 1984 (Box 99, Folder 3)
        - Improper Conduct, 1984 (Box 99, Folder 4)
      - 1984-1985
        - General, (2 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 5 to 6)
      - 1985-1986
        - General, (2 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 7 to 8)
        - Amerika, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 1)
        - Appropriation of Culture, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 2)
        - Atomic Bomb Films, 1982-1986 (Box 100, Folder 3)
        - Ballad of the Little Soldier, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 4)
        - Blood Simple, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 5)
        - Dark Glow of the Mountains, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 6)
        - Everything for Sale, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 7)
        - Gazdag, 1987 (Box 100, Folder 8)
        - Luxemburg, Rosa, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 9)
        - Partisans of Vilna, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 10)
        - The Purple Rose of Cairo, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 11)
        - Real Italian Pizza, 1971 (Box 100, Folder 12)
        - Salvador, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 13)
        - Seeing Red, 1983-1984 (Box 100, Folder 14)
        - Small Happiness, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 15)
        - Tokyo Fantasy, 1985 (Box 100, Folder 16)
        - We Were so Beloved, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 17)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 100, Folder 18)
      - 1987-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 1 to 4)
      - 1989-1990
        - General, 1989-1990 (Box 101, Folder 5)
        - General, 1989-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 102, Folder 1 to 3)
        - Angelopoulos, Théo, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 4)
        - Band of Four (Gang of Four), 1988 (Box 102, Folder 5)
        - Do the Right Thing, 1989 (Box 102, Folder 6)
        - Ethnic Notions, 1987 (Box 102, Folder 7)
        - Gertrud, 1964 (Box 102, Folder 8)
        - Landscape in Fog, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 9)
        - Powaqqatsi, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 10)
        - Vienna is Different, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 11)
        - Voyage to Cythera, 1984 (Box 102, Folder 12)
        - Whispers and Shouts, [1980s] (Box 102, Folder 13)
      - 1991-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder 1 to 2)
      - 1994, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Public Television Film Seminar, 1972, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Recommendation Letters, 1992-1996 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Rejected Films, 1972-1974 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Research for My New Book, 1995 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Riva Foundation, 1993-1996 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Rotterdam Film Festival, 1996 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Ruoff, Jeff, 1991 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Saint Petersburg, 1995 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Sarris, undated, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Scott--Two Amos Vogel Events, 1997 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Semiotics Conference, 1984 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Short Film Expo, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Socialist Scholars Conference, 1984 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Sontag, Susan, 1997 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Stammtisch with Philip Lopate, 1997-1998 (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Standard (Austria), 1993-1995 (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Talbot Cinema 16, undated (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - "Ten Years of Living Cinema," 1984 (Box 104, Folder 17)
    - Tyler, Parker, 1964-1967 (Box 104, Folder 18)
    - Veranderung im Film Colloquium-- Poster (Box 15-K-5)
    - Verleihkatalog, 1987-1988 (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - Video Stores, 1997 (Box 104, Folder 20)
    - Viennale, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Viennese Films, 1982 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Weiss, Marc, 1979-1980, 1996 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Wide-Angle: Cinema 16, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 4)
- Series III: Writings, 1896-1996
  Series III is comprised of Amos Vogel's writings in the form of manuscripts, lectures, essays, articles, and short-stories. The majority of the texts exist in multiple drafts, both typed and handwritten. Also included in this series are speeches Vogel gave at film events and lectures from his classes at various New York universities.
  - Subseries III.1: Manuscripts, 1896-1979
    Amos Vogel published his first book, Film as a Subversive Art, in 1974. Financial records, correspondence with the publishing house, research material, notes and stills (used and rejected) from the book are held in this subseries. There is one copy of the German translation in this subseries as well. Also included is material related to an unrealized book project entitled The Second Rape of the Marquise de O. This book was to be a critical analysis of Erich Romer's film based on the book by Heinrich von Kleist. Documents related to this project consist primarily of research notes written by Vogel, articles about Kleist in general, and the film, in particular, and drafts of proposals for funding.
    - Film as a Subversive Art, 1974
      - Complimentary Copies, 1975 (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - Falkus, Christopher, 1971-1973, (2 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 7 to 8)
      - German Edition--Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - German Edition--Manuscript, 1979 (Box 105, Folder 10)
      - Interviews, 1973-1975 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - Loomis, Robert, 1974-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 106, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Martin, Jonathan, 1971-1973, (2 Folders) (Box 106, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Notes, 1974-1975 (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - Potential Reviewers, 1975 (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - Proof with Annotations, 1975 (Box 147)
      - Publishing Bills, undated, 1973 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - Second Edition, [1970s] (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - Rejected Stills
        - Generals, 1970s (Box 106, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 106, Folder 10)
        - Worldview, 1950s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 11)
        - Russia, undated, 1926-1929, 1945 (Box 106, Folder 12)
        - Expressionism: The Cinema of Unrest, 1933-1971 (Box 107, Folder 1)
        - Surrealism: The Cinema of Shock, 1928-1971 (Box 107, Folder 2)
        - Dada and Pop: Anti-Art?, 1924-1965 (Box 107, Folder 3)
        - The Comic Tradition, 1918-1960 (Box 107, Folder 4)
        - The Destruction of Time and Space, 1903-1943 (Box 107, Folder 5)
        - The Destruction of Plot and Narrative, undated, 1959-1964 (Box 107, Folder 6)
        - The Assault on Montage, undated, 1960-1964 (Box 107, Folder 7)
        - The Camera Moves, 1927-1972 (Box 107, Folder 8)
        - Minimal Cinema, undated, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 9)
        - Straining towards the Limits, undated, 1955-1971 (Box 107, Folder 10)
        - The West: Rebels, Maoists, and the New Godard, 1933-1971 (Box 107, Folder 11)
        - Subversion in Eastern Europe: Aesopian Metaphors, 1965-1971 (Box 107, Folder 12)
        - The Third World: A New Cinema, undated, 1967-1971 (Box 107, Folder 13)
        - East Germany: Against the West, undated (Box 107, Folder 14)
        - The Terribly Poetry of Nazi Cinema, undated, 1938-1940 (Box 107, Folder 15)
        - Secrets and Revelations, 1928-1972 (Box 107, Folder 16)
        - [A, Most Desirable], 1943-1972 (Box 107, Folder 17)
        - The Attack on Puritanism: Nudity, undated, 1955-1971 (Box 107, Folder 18)
        - The End of Sexual Taboos: Erotic and Pornographic Cinema, 1896, 1929-1970 (Box 107, Folder 19)
        - The End of Sexual Taboos: Homosexuality and Other Variants, 1925-1970 (Box 108, Folder 1)
        - Death: 1948-1972 (Box 108, Folder 2)
        - The Attack on God: Blasphemy and Anti-clericalism, 1928-1971 (Box 108, Folder 3)
        - Trance and Witchcraft, 1916-1970 (Box 108, Folder 4)
        - Counterculture and Avant-Garde, 1935-1970 (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - Used Stills
        - General, 1929-1973 (Box 108, Folder 6)
        - Copies, undated (Box 108, Folder 7)
        - The World View of Subversive Cinema, 1955-1970 (Box 108, Folder 8)
        - The Revolutionary Film Avant-Garde in Soviet Russia, 1928-1966 (Box 108, Folder 9)
        - Expressionism: The Cinema of Unrest, 1920-1971 (Box 108, Folder 10)
        - Surrealism: The Cinema of Shock, 1929-1964 (Box 108, Folder 11)
        - Dada and Pop: Anti-Art?, undated, 1965-1967 (Box 108, Folder 12)
        - The Comic Tradition, undated, 1947 (Box 108, Folder 13)
        - The Destruction of Time and Space, 1943-1963 (Box 108, Folder 14)
        - The Destruction of Plot and Narrative, undated, 1960-1969 (Box 108, Folder 15)
        - The Assault on Montage, 1967, [1980] (Box 108, Folder 16)
        - Minimal Cinema, 1896, 1952-1972 (Box 108, Folder 17)
        - Straining towards the Limits, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 18)
        - The West: Rebels, Maoists, and the New Godard, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 19)
        - Subversion in Eastern Europe: Aesopian Metaphors, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 20)
        - The Third World: A New Cinema, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 21)
        - East Germany: Against the West, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 22)
        - The Terrible Poetry of Nazi Cinema, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 23)
        - Assorted Secrets, Revelations, and Seditions, 1920-1972 (Box 108, Folder 24)
        - The Power of the Visual Taboo, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 1)
        - The Attack on Puritanism: Nudity, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 2)
        - The End of Sexual Taboos: Erotic and Pornographic Cinema, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 3)
        - The End of Sexual Taboos: Homosexuality and Other Variants, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 4)
        - The First Mystery: Birth, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 5)
        - Death, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 6)
        - Concentration Camp, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 7)
        - The Attack on God: Blasphemy and Anti-clericalism, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 8)
        - Trance and Tears, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 9)
        - Counterculture and Avant-Garde, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 10)
        - The Subversion of Subversion, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 11)
        - The Eternal Subversion, 1920-1972 (Box 109, Folder 12)
        - Weidenfeld, 1975 (Box 109, Folder 13)
    - The Second Rape of the Marquise de O
      - Acknowledgements, [197-] (Box 109, Folder 14)
      - Advance Publicity of Excerpts, 1970 (Box 109, Folder 15)
      - Advertising Campaign, 1976 (Box 109, Folder 16)
      - Atmosphere/Ambiance (Box 109, Folder 17)
      - Bibliographic Research, 1978 (Box 109, Folder 18)
      - Bibliography, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 19)
      - Blow-Ups, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 20)
      - Camera, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 21)
      - Conclusions Drawn by Amos Vogel, undated, 1979 (Box 109, Folder 22)
      - Cover, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 23)
      - Credits for Film, 1976 (Box 109, Folder 24)
      - Dartmouth Symposium, 1977 (Box 109, Folder 25)
      - Décor/Sets, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 26)
      - Description of People, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 27)
      - Dialog and Text, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 28)
      - First Paragraph, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 29)
      - Fotos [sic], 1976 (Box 109, Folder 30)
      - Funding Sources for Book Research Grants, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 31)
      - Happy/Positive Events, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 32)
      - Intertitles, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 33)
      - Introduction with Hypothesis, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 34)
      - Introduction to Novella, undated, 1960 (Box 109, Folder 35)
      - Irony and Humor-Comedy or Tragedy?, 1970s (Box 109, Folder 36)
      - Kleist
        - General, 1979 (Box 109, Folder 37)
        - Articles, 1961-1977, (3 Folders) (Box 110, Folder 1 to 3)
        - His Worldview, 1977 (Box 110, Folder 4)
        - The Man-His Life, 1976 (Box 110, Folder 5)
      - Melodramatic Events, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Novella as Such: Meaning, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 7)
      - Novella--German and English, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 8)
      - Omissions and Additions, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 9)
      - Paintings as Prototypes, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 10)
      - Print Quality, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 11)
      - Prospectus
        - Earliest Version, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 12)
        - Guggenheim Version, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 13)
        - Latest Version, 1979 (Box 110, Folder 14)
      - Publishers, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 15)
      - Punctuation, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 16)
      - Rape, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 17)
      - Reprinting Rights, 1978 (Box 110, Folder 18)
      - Reviews, 1976-1977 (Box 110, Folder 19)
      - Rhythm, 1970s (Box 110, Folder 20)
      - Rohmer--The Director, 1976 (Box 110, Folder 21)
      - Rohmer--Intent, 1976 (Box 110, Folder 22)
      - Steenbeck Analysis, 1976-1977 (Box 111, Folder 1)
      - Structure of Book, 1977-1978 (Box 111, Folder 2)
      - Style, 1970s (Box 111, Folder 3)
      - Subtitles, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 4)
      - Synopsis of Story, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 5)
      - Title, 1978 (Box 111, Folder 6)
      - Trailer for Film, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - Translation as Such, 1970s (Box 111, Folder 8)
      - Unconscious and Its Role, 1970s (Box 111, Folder 9)
      - World Order References, 1970s (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Subseries III.2: Lectures and Speeches, 1957-1994
    This small subseries holds speeches written by Amos Vogel for notable film events, such as the American Film Institute's Maya Deren event and the Pacific Film Archive's film conference. Lectures given at a range of academic institutions are also held here. Note that these lectures were conducted on a one-time basis. Semester-long academic lectures are found in Subseries III.3.
    - General, undated, 1995 (Box 146, Folder 18)
    - Alternative Cinema Conference, 1979 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - American Film Awards: Maya Deren Award, 1987 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - American Library Association--New Technologies, 1980 June (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Amos Vogel Colloquium, undated (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - "Artist and Peace," 1957?-1960 ? (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Berlin Speech, undated, 1999 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Columbia University, 1977 April (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Connecticut Center for Continuing Education, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - COVA Conference on Herzog, 1978 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - "Cultural Gap and Future," 1970 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Denison University, 1986 January (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - EFLA
      - "Political Cinema," 1971 November (Box 111, Folder 22)
      - "Film as Art," 1975 (Box 111, Folder 23)
      - "Film as Art," 1976 (Box 111, Folder 24)
      - "Film as Art," 1980 (Box 111, Folder 25)
    - "Exhibiting Independent Films," 1971 (Box 111, Folder 26)
    - Free Time (Channel 13 Television Show), 1971 May (Box 111, Folder 27)
    - German Symposium, 1991 January 15 (Box 111, Folder 28)
    - Hampshire College, 1980 April (Box 111, Folder 29)
    - Harvard Speech, 1977 May (Box 111, Folder 30)
    - Introduction to Shadows and Pull My Daisy, undated (Box 111, Folder 31)
    - Makavajev Talk at Eastern European Film Festival, 1986 (Box 111, Folder 32)
    - National Endowment for the Arts Panel, 1983-1984 (Box 111, Folder 33)
    - New York Film Council--"Film as a Subversive Art," [1974-1975] (Box 111, Folder 34)
    - New York Filmvideo Council, 1984 September 20 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - New York Filmvideo Council--"Pioneers," 1985 February 21 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - New York Nonprofit Film Exhibitors, 1987 January (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Northwest Film and Video Festival, 1981 April (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Pacific Film Archive--"Cinema 16," 1990 April 17 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Pacific Film Archive--"Film as a Subversive Art," 1990 April 18 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Pesaro Festival of Independent Cinema, 1991 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Portland, 1980 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Pro-Seminar, 1978-1979 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Reel Philadelphia, 1980 October (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Right-Wing Propaganda, 1971 March 30 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1978 October 21 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - "Social Realism and Avant-Garde," 1989 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Temple University, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - "Time, Space, and Truth in Cinema," 1974 April (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - Trenton--Bucks County Community College, 1982 December 13 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - Tyler School of Arts, 1985 February 6 (Box 112, Folder 17)
    - "Victims and Survivors," undated (Box 112, Folder 18)
    - Wisconsin University, 1984 May 2 (Box 112, Folder 19)
    - Wolfgang Staudte Award Ceremony, 1994 (Box 112, Folder 20)
  - Subseries III.3: Academic Courses, 1951-1995
    Subseries 3 consists primarily of documents relating to courses that Amos Vogel taught at the Annenberg School of Communication at the University of Pennsylvania. Each course section contains the syllabi of films to be screened as well as assignments, podium notes, including the timing for screening the films, printed material, such as flyers and bulletins advertising the courses, and Vogel's own class notes. These last documents are especially salient as they illuminate Vogel's thought process and illustrate one way that film courses can develop over a semester. There is a small amount of material from courses Vogel taught at New York University, the New School, and other unnamed academic institutions.
    - Annenberg--General, 1990-1992 (Box 112, Folder 21)
    - Annenberg Cinemathique, 1974-1979 (Box 112, Folder 22)
    - Annenberg 220, 1976--Printed Material (Box 112, Folder 23)
    - Annenberg 220, 1978
      - Session I, 1978-1983 (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - Session II, 1978-1989 (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Session III, 1978-1985 (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Session IV, 1978-1985 (Box 113, Folder 4)
      - Session V, 1978-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 113, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Session XII, 1978 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Annenberg 220--"World View," 1980
      - Session I through III, 1980 (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Session VI, 1980-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 114, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Session VII, 1980-1990 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      - Session VIII, 1980-1989 (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - Session IX, 1980-1988 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - Session X and XI, 1980-1983 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - Session XII, 1980 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - Session XIII, 1980-1988 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Annenberg 320--"Manipulation and Ideology in Film," 1982
      - Master Lists, 1982 (Box 115, Folder 5)
      - Printed Material, 1982 (Box 115, Folder 6)
      - Session I, 1982-1988 (Box 115, Folder 7)
      - Session II, 1982-1989 (Box 115, Folder 8)
      - Session III, 1982-1991 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Session IV, 1982-1990 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Session V, 1982-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 116, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Session VI, 1982-1985 (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - Session VII, 1982-1985 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - Session IX, 1982-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 117, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Slide Sets, 1982 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      - Session VIII, 1984-1989 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - Session X, 1984-1988 (Box 117, Folder 5)
      - Session XI, 1984-1989 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - Annenberg 320, 1985 (Box 118)
      - General, 1985 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - Session VI, 1985-1989 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      - Session VII, 1985-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Annenberg 320--"Protection," 1986
      - Sessions I through IV, 1986 (Box 118, Folder 5)
      - Sessions V through VII, 1986 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Sessions IIX through X, 1986 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - Session XI, 1986 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Annenberg 320, 1987 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Annenberg 320, [1980s]
      - Bibliography, [1980s], (3 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 3 to 5)
      - FAS Submission, 1980s (Box 119, Folder 6)
      - Films, 1980s, (4 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Master Copy, 1980s (Box 120, Folder 5)
      - Teaching Associate Handbook, 1989 (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - Thoughts, 1980s (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - Type, 1980s (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - Type Hawkers, 1980s (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - Unresolved Questions, 1980s (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - Video at Studio Theatre, 1980s (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Annenberg 520--"Methods of Film Analysis," 1977
      - Reading List, 1977 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - Session I, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 7)
      - Session II, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 8)
      - Session III, 1977-1978 (Box 121, Folder 9)
      - Session IV, 1977-1978 (Box 122, Folder 1)
      - Session V, 1977-1990 (Box 122, Folder 2)
      - Session VI, 1977-1978 (Box 122, Folder 3)
      - Session VII, 1977-1978 (Box 122, Folder 4)
      - Session VIII, 1977-1978 (Box 122, Folder 5)
      - Session IX, 1977 (Box 122, Folder 6)
      - Session X, 1977-1978 (Box 123, Folder 1)
      - Session XI, 1977-1978 (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Session XII, 1977-1978 (Box 123, Folder 3)
      - Last Session, 1977-1978 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Annenberg 520--Bibliography, 1970s-1980s (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Individual Lecture Topics
      - General, 1967-1984 (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - General, 1967-1984 (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - "Before the Revolution," 1980s (Box 124, Folder 2)
      - "Manipulation and Ideology in Film," 1982 Spring (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - "Sources of Modern Cinema," 1987 (Box 124, Folder 4)
      - "Touch of Evil," 1980s (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Master List for Teaching, 1967-1971 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - New School: Censored Cinema, 1970s (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - New York University
      - Correspondence and Faculty Matters, 1967 (Box 124, Folder 8)
      - "Film as a Subversive Art," 1971 (Box 124, Folder 9)
      - "Film as a Subversive Art," 1980 (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - "Film as Visual Art," 1969 (Box 125, Folder 2)
      - "Issues in Modern Cinema," 1974-1980 (Box 125, Folder 3)
      - Myth Course, 1961-1980, (2 Folders) (Box 125, Folder 4 to 5)
      - 320, 1986
        - Sessions I through IV, 1986 (Box 125, Folder 6)
        - Sessions V through VII, 1986 (Box 126, Folder 1)
        - Sessions VIII through X, 1986 (Box 126, Folder 2)
        - Sessions XI, 1986 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Other Courses
      - General, 1951-1995 (Box 126, Folder 4)
      - "Alienation," undated (Box 126, Folder 5)
      - Bibliography, 1970s-1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 126, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Bibliography, 1970s-1980s (Box 127, Folder 1)
      - "Codes of Modern Cinema," 1981 (Box 127, Folder 2)
      - Course File, 1979-1982 (Box 127, Folder 3)
      - "Film and Modernism," undated (Box 127, Folder 4)
      - "Kleist/Rohmer," 1979 Spring (Box 127, Folder 5)
      - Potential Classes, 1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 127, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Potential Syllabi, 1980s (Box 127, Folder 8)
      - "Pro-Semiotics," 1981 (Box 127, Folder 9)
      - "Semantic Analysis," 1977 (Box 127, Folder 10)
      - "The Sixties," 1970s (Box 127, Folder 11)
      - "Sources of Modern Cinema," 1990 Fall (Box 127, Folder 12)
      - Syllabi, 1981-1982 (Box 127, Folder 13)
      - "Theory of Film," undated (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - Reading Material, 1967-1984, (3 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Subseries III.4: Short Stories, 1960-1985
    Subseries 4 is the smallest of Series III and holds short stories, often with multiple annotated drafts accompanying the final product. Some of these stories were written for children, such as "The Hamburger Hold-up" and "Loring and the Skyscraper." Not present is the Maurice Sendak illustrated "How Little Loring went to Times Square." Stories for adults include pieces concerned with genocide, in particular the Holocaust, memory, relationships between individuals, spirituality and faith, and societal roles and mores.
    - General, undated, 1960-1981 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - "Department Store Dogs," 1978 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - "The Execution," 1981-1985 (Box 128, Folder 6)